Register of the William H. Rehnquist papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1969-2005
  - General, 2004-2005
    - W, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 171: 11)
    - Y-Z, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 171: 12)
  - Supreme Court justices, 2004-2005
    - 2004 (Box-folder 171: 13-14)
    - 2005 (Box-folder 171: 15)
  - Family, 1975-2005
    - General, 1976-2005 (Box-folder 172: 1)
    - Brachman, Arlene and Bob, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 172: 2)
    - Laurin, Jean R., 1975-2005 (Box-folder 172: 3)
    - Rehnquist, James, 1975-2002 (Box-folder 172: 4)
    - Rehnquist, Janet, 1975-1989 (Box-folder 172: 5)
    - Rehnquist, Margery Peck, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 172: 6)
    - Rehnquist, Margery P. (mother) condolences, 1988 (Box-folder 358: 1-3)
    - Rehnquist, N. Alden, 1980-1991 (Box-folder 172: 7)
    - Rehnquist, Thomas, 2003 (Box-folder 172: 8)
    - Rehnquist, Tim, 1989-2004 (Box-folder 172: 9)
    - Sawday, Ann, 1983 (Box-folder 172: 10)
    - Spears (née Rehnquist), Nancy, 1978-2002 (Box-folder 172: 11)
- Books, 1974-2005
  Contains proposals, outlines, drafts, production materials, published works, correspondence, photographs, and interviews related to books written by Rehnquist and documenting Rehnquist's writing process on each of his books from initial idea to finished work. In addition to material regarding his judicial and political histories, the series also includes notes and proposals for works of fiction that were never published. Arranged in five subseries, each consisting of files for a different book or project. The subseries are arranged in chronological order according to the publication date of each book.
  - The Supreme Court: How It Was, How It Is, 1983-2005
    Consists of drafts, production materials, correspondence, photographs, and requests to sign Rehnquist's first book, a history of the Supreme Court. Also includes the revisions, correspondence, and production material documenting the new revised edition, published in 2001. The original order of the subseries has been maintained: drafts and production materials appear in chronological order, followed by correspondence and notes in alphabetical order of folder title
    - First draft chapters 1-2, 1985 (Box-folder 173: 1-2)
    - First draft chapters 3-5, 1985 (Box-folder 173: 3)
    - First draft chapters 4-7, 1985 (Box-folder 173: 4)
    - First draft chapter 6, 1985 Sept. 23 (Box-folder 173: 5)
    - First draft chapter 9, 1985 Sept. 12 (Box-folder 173: 6)
    - First draft chapters 11-13, 1986 (Box-folder 173: 7)
    - Drafts chapter 3, 1985 Sept. 4 (Box-folder 173: 8)
    - Drafts chapter 3, 1986 June 6 (Box-folder 173: 9)
    - Drafts chapter 5, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 173: 10)
    - Drafts chapter 6, 1985 September (Box-folder 174: 1-2)
    - Drafts chapters 5-6, 1985 Sept. 23 (Box-folder 174: 3)
    - Drafts chapter 7, 1985 September (Box-folder 174: 4)
    - Drafts chapters 8-9, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 174: 5)
    - Drafts chapters 10-11, 1986 (Box-folder 174: 6)
    - Drafts chapter 12, 1986 (Box-folder 174: 7)
    - Drafts chapters 13-14, 1986 (Box-folder 174: 8)
    - Manuscript, 1987 (Box-folder 174: 9)
    - Manuscript, 1987 (Box-folder 175: 1-4)
    - Final manuscript, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 175: 5-8)
    - Proofs, 1987 (Box-folder 176: 1-2)
    - Corrections, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 176: 3)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 176: 4)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 176: 5)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box-folder 176: 6-8)
    - Beyond War: A New Way Of Thinking, audiocassette, 1987 (Box-folder 194: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1999 (Box-folder 176: 9)
    - Notes, 1985 (Box-folder 177: 1)
    - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 177: 2)
    - Reference Photographs, 1987 (Box-folder 177: 3)
    - Requests to sign, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 177: 4)
      Includes photographs
    - Requests to sign, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 177: 5)
    - Requests to sign, 1988-2003 (Box-folder 177: 6)
    - Royalties, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 177: 7)
    - The Supreme Court, published book, 1992 (Box-folder 177: 8)
      In Japanese
    - Revised edition edited manuscript, 2000 (Box-folder 177: 9)
    - Revised edition edited manuscript, 2000 (Box-folder 178: 1-4)
    - Revised edition setting copy, 2000 (Box-folder 178: 5-8)
    - Revised edition corrected galleys, 2000 (Box-folder 178: 9)
    - Revised edition corrected galleys, 2000 (Box-folder 179: 1-2)
    - Revised edition correspondence, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 179: 3)
      Includes photographs.
    - Revised edition Knopf correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 179: 4)
    - Revised edition Knopf correspondence, 2001-2005 (Box-folder 179: 5)
    - Revised edition requests to sign, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 179: 6)
    - Revised edition requests to sign, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 179: 7)
  - Grand Inquests: The Historic Impeachments of Justice Samuel Chase and President Andrew Johnson, 1989-2003
    Consists of drafts, production materials, correspondence, photographs, and requests to sign Rehnquist's second book, a history of impeachment in the United States. Also includes first edition and reprinted copies of the published book. The original order of the subseries has been maintained: drafts and production materials appear in chronological order, followed by correspondence and notes in alphabetical order of folder title.
    - Draft chapters 1-2, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 180: 1)
    - Draft chapters 3-6, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 180: 2)
    - Draft chapters 7-9, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 180: 3)
    - Draft chapters 10-11, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 180: 4)
    - Draft chapters 12-14, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 180: 5)
    - Draft chapters 9-14, 1990 Nov. 28 (Box-folder 180: 6)
    - Draft preface and chapter 15-17, 1991 (Box-folder 180: 7)
    - Edited draft preface and chapter 3-5, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 180: 8)
    - Edited draft chapters 6-9, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 181: 1)
    - Edited draft chapters 10-12, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 181: 2)
    - Edited draft chapters 13-17, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 181: 3)
    - Manuscript, 1991 Oct. 16 (Box-folder 181: 4-8)
    - Galleys, 1991 December (Box-folder 181: 9-10)
    - Production materials, 1991 November (Box-folder 182: 1-5)
    - Production materials, 1991 November-December (Box-folder 182: 6-7)
    - Production materials, 1992 January (Box-folder 182: 8-9)
    - Production materials, 1992 February 6 (Box-folder 183: 1-3)
    - Production materials, 1992 February 10 (Box-folder 183: 4-6)
    - Uncorrected bound galleys, 1992 (Box-folder 183: 7)
    - Grand Inquests: The Historic Impeachments of Justice Samuel Chase and President Andrew Johnson First edition, published book, 1992 (Box-folder 183: 8)
    - Contracts, 1989 (Box-folder 184: 1)
    - Corrections, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 184: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 184: 3)
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box-folder 184: 4)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 184: 5-6)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 184: 7)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 184: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 184: 9)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2003 (Box-folder 184: 10)
    - Photographs, 1991 (Box-folder 185: 1)
    - Requests to sign, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 185: 2-3)
    - Requests to sign, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 185: 4)
    - Requests to sign, 1994-2000 (Box-folder 185: 5)
    - Requests to sign, 1998-2003 (Box-folder 185: 6)
    - Reprinting correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 185: 7)
    - Grand Inquests: The Historic Impeachments of Justice Samuel Chase and President Andrew Johnson Reprinted, published book, 1999 (Box-folder 185: 8)
    - Royalties, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 186: 1)
  - All the Laws But One: Civil Liberties in Wartime, 1994-2005
    Consists of a book outline, drafts, production materials, correspondence, interviews, and requests to sign Rehnquist's third book, a history of civil liberties during the Civil War and World Wars I and II. Also includes the published book. The original order of the subseries has been maintained: drafts and production materials appear in chronological order, followed by correspondence and notes in alphabetical order of folder title
    - Draft chapters 1-3, undated (Box-folder 186: 2)
    - Draft chapters 4-6, undated (Box-folder 186: 3)
    - Draft chapters 7-9, undated (Box-folder 186: 4)
    - Draft chapters 10-13, undated (Box-folder 186: 5)
    - Draft chapters 14-15, undated (Box-folder 186: 6)
    - Draft chapters 21-23, undated (Box-folder 186: 7)
    - Draft, 1995 (Box-folder 186: 8-9)
    - Draft, 1997 (Box-folder 186: 10-11)
    - Draft, 1997 (Box-folder 187: 1-3)
    - Edited draft, 1998 Jan. 28 (Box-folder 187: 4-7)
    - Manuscript, 1998 (Box-folder 187: 8-9)
    - Manuscript, 1998 (Box-folder 188: 1-2)
    - Galleys first pass, 1998 April (Box-folder 188: 3-5)
    - Galleys second pass, 1998 May (Box-folder 188: 6-8)
    - All the Laws But One: Civil Liberties in Wartime, published book, 1998 (Box-folder 188: 9)
    - Book Party, 1998 (Box-folder 189: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 189: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1997 (Box-folder 189: 3)
    - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 189: 4-5)
    - Correspondence, 1998 (Box-folder 189: 6-7)
    - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 189: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 190: 1-2)
    - Outline, 1995 (Box-folder 190: 3)
    - Requests to sign, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 190: 4)
    - Requests to sign, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 190: 5)
    - Requests to sign, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 190: 6)
    - Royalties, 1998-2005 (Box-folder 190: 7)
    - Television Interviews, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 190: 8)
    - Newshour Interview, videocassette, 1998 Nov. 11 (Box-folder 194: 2)
  - Centennial Crisis: The Disputed Election of 1876, 2001-2005
    Consists of drafts, production materials, correspondence, interviews, and requests to sign Rehnquist's fourth book, which describes the Congressional Commission that resolved the disputed presidential election between Samuel Tilden and Rutherford B. Hayes. Also includes the published book. The original order of the subseries has been maintained: drafts and production materials appear in chronological order, followed by correspondence and notes in alphabetical order of folder title.
    - Draft prologue and chapter 1-3, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 191: 1)
    - Draft chapter 4, 2002 (Box-folder 191: 2)
    - Draft chapter 5-6, 2002 (Box-folder 191: 3)
    - Draft chapter 8-10, 2003 (Box-folder 191: 4)
    - Draft chapter 10, 2003 (Box-folder 191: 5)
    - Final footnote changes, 2003 (Box-folder 191: 6-9)
    - Galleys second pass, 2003 (Box-folder 191: 10)
    - Galleys second pass, 2003 (Box-folder 192: 1-2)
    - Uncorrected proof, 2003 (Box-folder 192: 3)
    - Centennial Crisis: The Disputed Election of 1876, published book, 2003 (Box-folder 192: 4)
    - Correspondence, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 192: 5)
    - Correspondence, 2003 (Box-folder 192: 6-7)
    - Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 192: 8)
    - Interviews, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 192: 9)
    - New York Times Interview with Dinita Smith, audiocassette, 2004 Mar. 5 (Box-folder 194: 3)
    - Today Show Interview, videocassette, 2004 Mar. 10 (Box-folder 194: 4)
    - Charlie Rose Interview, videocassette, 2004 Mar. 11 (Box-folder 194: 5)
    - Requests to sign, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 193: 1)
    - Reviews, 2004 (Box-folder 193: 2)
    - Royalty statements, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 193: 3)
  - Other Projects, 1974-2005
    - Book notes, undated (Box-folder 193: 4)
    - Correspondence with Robert Lantz, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 193: 5)
    - Novel notes, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 193: 6)
    - Death in the Paw-Paw Tunnel Book Outline, 1994 (Box-folder 193: 7)
    - Custer's Last Stand Book proposal, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 193: 8)
    - Books returned unsigned, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 193: 9)
    - Night Watch by Stephen Kendrick, manuscript, undated (Box-folder 193: 10-11)
- Speeches and Writings, 1971-2005
  In addition to Rehnquist's many official remarks, largely pertaining to issues of constitutional law and the functioning of the American judicial system, this series includes a number of articles, as well as materials relating to his visiting lectureships at the University of Arizona and as part of summer programs run by American universities in the United Kingdom and Europe. There are also numerous speeches given on ceremonial occasions in which Rehnquist appeared in his capacity as Chief Justice of the United States.
  The series contains a good deal of accompanying material, largely consisting of correspondence, and in some cases, printed matter used in the preparation of speeches. A number of folders contain neither speeches nor writings, but rather correspondence and other documents relating to various moot court panels that Rehnquist served on, meetings that he attended, and, in one case, his brief tenure, on special assignment, as a circuit justice. There are also a number of prints that depict Rehnquist at speaking engagements. It is noted in the register when only correspondence, and not the text itself, is available for a particular speech.
  The original arrangement of the materials has been maintained.
  - Topical index, 1989 (Box-folder 198: 1)
  - Speech on detection technology and civil liberties, New School for Social Research, New York City, 1971 October 6 (Box-folder 198: 2)
    Typescript and correspondence
  - Seminar, Bradley Hills Presbyterian Church, Bethesda, Maryland, 1971 October 10 (Box-folder 198: 3)
    Correspondence only
  - Lecture on dissent and civil disobedience, University of California, Los Angeles, 1971 November 16 (Box-folder 198: 4)
  - Speech, Assistant United States Attorneys Association for the District of Columbia banquet, Washington, D.C., 1972 March 25 (Box-folder 198: 5)
  - Moot court panel discussion, University of Chicago, 1972 May 8 (Box-folder 198: 6)
  - Speech, Judicial Conference of the Seventh Circuit, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1972 May 8 (Box-folder 198: 7)
  - Speech, Young Lawyers Section, Bar Association of the District of Columbia, Washington, D.C., 1972 May 17 (Box-folder 198: 8)
  - Speeches, Arizona State University, Tempe, Arizona, 1972 June 1-2 (Box-folder 198: 9)
    Correspondence and clipping only
  - Commencement address, Orme School, Mayer, Arizona, 1972 June 3 (Box-folder 198: 10)
  - Time: A Necessary Ingredient of the Appellate Process, Conference of State Chief Justices, Seattle, Washington, 1972 August 11 (Box-folder 198: 11)
  - Invitee, Judicial Conference of the Eighth Circuit, Omaha, Nebraska, 1972 August 27 (Box-folder 198: 12)
  - Speech, Young Federal Lawyers Luncheon, Washington, D.C., 1972 September 13 (Box-folder 198: 13)
  - Speech, Louisville and Kentucky Bar Associations joint meeting, Louisville, Kentucky, 1972 September 21 (Box-folder 198: 14)
    Typescript, correspondence, clipping, and photographs
  - Speech, American Whig-Cliosophical Society, Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey, 1972 October 26 (Box-folder 198: 15)
  - Speech, Fall Pastoral Conference, Pilgrim Lutheran Church, Bethesda, Maryland, 1972 October 31 (Box-folder 198: 16)
  - Speech, Kiwanis Club, McLean, Virginia, 1972 November 2 (Box-folder 198: 17)
    Typescript notes and correspondence
  - Address, Chicago Bar Association, Chicago, Illinois, 1972 November 29 (Box-folder 198: 18)
  - Speech, Palm Beach County Bar Association, 1973 January 3 (Box-folder 199: 1)
    Correspondence and clippings only
  - Talk, Student Bar Association, Catholic University of America, Washington, D.C., 1973 January 23 (Box-folder 199: 2)
  - Address, National Conference on Criminal Justice, Washington, D.C., 1973 January 25 (Box-folder 199: 3)
  - Address, Fellows of the American Bar Foundation, Cleveland, Ohio, 1973 February 10 (Box-folder 199: 4)
    Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence
  - Campbell Moot Court Competition, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1973 March 6 (Box-folder 199: 5)
    (cancelled appearance).
  - The Varieties of Legal Experience, Duke Law Forum, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina, 1973 April 4 (Box-folder 199: 6)
  - Remarks, Marion Rice Kirkwood Competition, Stanford University, Stanford, California, 1973 April 7 (Box-folder 199: 7)
  - Civility and Freedom of Speech, Law Day address, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana, 1973 April 24 (Box-folder 199: 8)
    Typescript, printed copy, clipping, and correspondence
  - Remarks, Office of the General Counsel of the Department of the Navy annual dinner, Fort McNair Officers Club, Washington, D.C., 1973 May 1 (Box-folder 199: 9)
  - Moot court competition, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign, Illinois, 1973 May 14 (Box-folder 199: 10)
  - Speech, Bar Association of the Seventh Circuit, Chicago, Illinois, 1973 May 15 (Box-folder 199: 11)
  - Commencement speech, Mona Shores High School, Muskegon, Michigan, 1973 June 3 (Box-folder 200: 1)
  - Commencement speech, Langley High School, McLean, Virginia, 1973 June 9 (Box-folder 200: 2)
  - Speech, State Bar of Wisconsin annual dinner, Delavan, Wisconsin, 1973 June 20 (Box-folder 200: 3)
  - Speech, Brookings Institution, Washington, D.C., 1973 July 13 (Box-folder 200: 4)
    Correspondence and program only
  - Speech, Loyola College, Baltimore, Maryland, 1973 September 11 (Box-folder 200: 5)
  - Sense and Nonsense about Judicial Ethics, speech, Association of the Bar of the City of New York, New York City, 1973 September 19 (Box-folder 200: 6)
    Printed copy
  - Legal Education: A Consumer's Point of View, speech, University of Tulsa, Tulsa, Oklahoma, 1974 January 23 (Box-folder 200: 7)
  - Moot court panel, Notre Dame Law School, Notre Dame, Indiana, 1974 January 26 (Box-folder 200: 8)
  - National Prayer Breakfast, Washington, D.C., 1974 January 31 (Box-folder 200: 9)
  - Moot court panel, University of Michigan Law School, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1974 March 12 (Box-folder 200: 10)
  - Remarks, American Bar Association National Institute, Washington, D.C., 1974 March 14 (Box-folder 200: 11)
  - Lecture, College of Law, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, 1974 April 10 (Box-folder 200: 12)
  - Dilemmas of Conscience in the Exercise of Power, Symposium on Christian Social Responsibility, Trinity College, Washington, D.C., 1974 April 19 (Box-folder 201: 1)
  - Whither the Courts, speech, State Bar of Arizona convention, Phoenix, Arizona, 1974 May 2 (Box-folder 201: 2)
  - Moot court panel, Northwestern University School of Law, Chicago, Illinois, 1974 May 13 (Box-folder 201: 3)
  - Speech, Judicial Conference of the Seventh Federal Circuit, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1974 May 15 (Box-folder 201: 4)
  - Judicial Conference of the Fourth Circuit, White Sulfur Springs, West Virginia, 1974 June 26 (Box-folder 201: 5)
    (cancelled appearance). Correspondence only
  - What Lawyers Ought to Know about Judges, speech, State Bar of California annual meeting, Sacramento, California, 1974 September 11 (Box-folder 201: 6)
  - Is an Expanded Right to Privacy Consistent with Fair and Effective Law Enforcement? Or: Privacy, You've Come a Long Way, Baby, lecture, School of Law, University of Kansas, Lawrence, Kansas, 1974 September 26-27 (Box-folder 201: 7)
    Typescript, printed copy, clippings, and correspondence
  - Speech, National Law Center, George Washington University, Washington, D.C., 1974 October 30 (Box-folder 201: 8)
  - Moot court panel, Association of the Bar of the City of New York, New York City, 1974 December 4 (Box-folder 201: 9)
  - Speech, Harvard Law School Association of the District of Columbia, Washington, D.C., 1975 January 16 (Box-folder 202: 1)
  - Public Officials: Are They Public Property? speech, Washington and Lee University, Lexington, Virginia, 1975 March 4 (Box-folder 202: 2)
    Typescript, correspondence, and program
  - Moot court panel, Cornell Law School, Ithaca, New York, 1975 March 7 (Box-folder 202: 3)
  - Moot court panel, Syracuse University School of Law, Syracuse, New York, 1975 March 8 (Box-folder 202: 4)
  - Moot court panel, College of Law, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, 1975 April 4 (Box-folder 202: 5)
  - Political Battles for Judicial Independence, speech, University of Washington Law School, Seattle, Washington, 1975 May 5 (Box-folder 202: 6)
  - Speech, Judicial Conference of the Seventh Circuit, Chicago, Illinois, 1975 May 13 (Box-folder 202: 7)
  - Remarks, Dartmouth College, Hanover, New Hampshire, 1975 May 21 (Box-folder 202: 8)
  - Remarks, Vermont Law School, South Royalton, Vermont, 1975 May 22 (Box-folder 202: 9)
  - Speech, Covington & Burling luncheon, Washington, D.C., 1975 July 1 (Box-folder 202: 10)
  - Speech, American Bar Association annual meeting, Montreal, Canada, 1975 August 11 (Box-folder 202: 11)
  - When Is Justice Done? lecture, Trial Advocacy Course, Department of Justice, Washington, D.C., 1975 September 8 (Box-folder 202: 12)
  - Speech, Bull Elephants luncheon, Washington, D.C., 1975 September 17 (Box-folder 202: 13)
  - A Government of Laws and of Men: A Bicentennial View of the Judicial Branch, lecture, Indiana University, Fort Wayne, Indiana, 1975 September 23 (Box-folder 202: 14)
  - Remarks, Washington Alumni of Harvard's Kennedy School of Government luncheon, Washington, D.C., 1975 October 3 (Box-folder 202: 15)
  - Remarks, Department of Politics class, Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey, 1975 October 21 (Box-folder 202: 16)
  - Moot court panel, University of Pennsylvania Law School, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1975 November 18 (Box-folder 202: 17)
  - Seminar, Georgetown University Law Center, Washington, D.C., 1975 November 25 (Box-folder 202: 18)
  - Public Opinion and Supreme Court Appointments, Calvin Bullock Forum, New York City, 1976 January 27 (Box-folder 203: 1)
  - Remarks, White House Fellows meeting, Washington, D.C., 1976 February 4 (Box-folder 203: 2)
  - Chief Justices I Never Knew, lecture, Hastings College of the Law, University of California, San Francisco, California, 1976 February 12 (Box-folder 203: 3)
  - Better Dead than Read: The Notion of a Living Constitution, Orgain Lecture, School of Law, University of Texas, Austin, Texas, 1976 March 12 (Box-folder 203: 4)
    Typescript, correspondence, clippings, and photographs
  - Remarks, American Bar Association Bicentennial Institute, Washington, D.C., 1976 March 18 (Box-folder 203: 5)
  - Speech, Student Legal Forum, University of Virginia School of Law, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1976 April 1 (Box-folder 203: 6)
    (cancelled appearance)
  - Speech, Lutheran Laymen's Fellowship, Washington, D.C., 1976 April 2 (Box-folder 203: 7)
  - Moot court panel, School of Law, Columbia University, New York City, 1976 April 6 (Box-folder 203: 8)
  - The Supreme Court in a Democratic Society, address, University of Nebraska, Omaha, Nebraska, 1976 April 14 (Box-folder 203: 9)
  - Moot court panel, University of Virginia School of Law, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1976 April 24 (Box-folder 203: 10)
  - Remarks, Phi Delta Phi meeting, Suffolk University Law School, Boston, Massachusetts, 1976 May 3 (Box-folder 203: 11)
  - Speech, Gettysburg College, Gettysburg, Pennsylvania, 1976 May 7 (Box-folder 203: 12)
  - Remarks, Bar Association of the Seventh Circuit annual meeting, French Lick, Indiana, 1976 May 11 (Box-folder 204: 1)
  - A View from the Bench, speech, Homer Ferguson Conference on Appellate Advocacy, Georgetown University Law Center, 1976 May 21 (Box-folder 204: 2)
  - Commencement speech, Wittenberg University, Springfield, Ohio, 1976 June (Box-folder 204: 3)
    Typescript and correspondence.
  - Remarks, Judicial Conference of the Ninth Circuit, Spokane, Washington, 1976 July 27 (Box-folder 204: 4)
  - "The Cult of the Robe,1976, American Bar Association annual dinner, Atlanta, Georgia, ", 1976 August 9 (Box-folder 204: 5)
  - Lecture, University of Wisconsin Law School, Madison, Wisconsin, 1976 September 17 (Box-folder 204: 6)